<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Keyboards on ursaw</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/tags/keyboards/</link><description>Recent content in Keyboards on ursaw</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 21:49:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ursaw.github.io/tags/keyboards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prebuild Ergo Mechanical Keyboards</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/prebuild-ergo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 21:49:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/prebuild-ergo/</guid><description>Ergo keyboards tend to be a nerdy topic, where you quite soon came to a point where you need to do DYI with soldering. Ergonomics in keyboards ia at least the three angles and ends up in highly subject aspects.
I want to give an overview of available (prebuilt) models for newbies into the ergo mechanical keyboard scene. I have no experience with most of them, but I hope this represents the market of 2023.</description></item><item><title>My Keyboard Evolution</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/my_keyboard_evolution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/my_keyboard_evolution/</guid><description>TL;DR This is my historically ordered journey into ergonomic keyboards. I try to explain the background of each choice, the advantages and limitations.
My main work on computers is coding, and I like terminals/consoles and try avoid using the mouse as much as possible.
From IBM model M to Dactyl split ortho keyboard for ergonomics and fun. I am still use QWERTY, but slowly moving to COLMAK DH.
It was an evolution with many small changes, today I advise a quick jump to a split ortho keyboard or mono blocks.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Keyboards</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/keyboards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/keyboards/</guid><description>Recently I digged into ergonomical mechanical split keyboards, which become a time consumption hobby due the corona times.
I like thinking of and building ergonomic input devices, especially keyboards, unfortunately its not only a hobby I also need it because of some pains due long working at the machine.
Links https://geekhack.org
https://deskthority.net
https://www.reddit.com/r/ErgoMechKeyboards, https://www.reddit.com/r/olkb
https://kbd.news, https://golem.hu
https://jhelvy.shinyapps.io/splitkbcompare
https://docs.qmk.fm</description></item><item><title>Some experience and thoughts about Sofle V1</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/thoughts_soflev1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/thoughts_soflev1/</guid><description>Two months ago I built a Sofle V1(Zealios 67g, DSA caps) that is my daily driver, but I have to admit that I am not as happy as I think I could or should be&amp;hellip;
The reasons are the following:
This is my first column staggered keyboard, I had a few split afore because I am starting to suffer from RSI. When I switched from the Quefrency keyboard to the Sofle keyboard, I got quite a bit of pain extending from my thumb to my neck, which surprised me quite a bit because I thought it would be more ergonomic.</description></item></channel></rss>