<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on ursaw</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on ursaw</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 13:42:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ursaw.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Python dataclasses</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/python_dataclasses/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 13:42:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/python_dataclasses/</guid><description>Background Although I work quite much with python I really hate the aspect of dynamically typing when using classes. In my opinion you should do on object oriented modelling to define attributes instead of adding attributes during runtime.
I would like to have something like perls use strict to at least define the attributes, even if the datatype is missing there.
Python 3.7, pep 557 introduced dataclasses to the default library, which enables the developer to do an object oriented modelling with python.</description></item><item><title>Ergo Keyboards</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/keyboards/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/keyboards/</guid><description>Recently I digged into ergonomical mechanical split keyboards, which become a time consumption hobby due the corona times.
I like thinking of and building ergonomic input devices, especially keyboards, unfortunately its not only a hobby I also need it because of some pains due long working at the machine.
Links https://kbd.news/, https://golem.hu
https://www.reddit.com/r/ErgoMechKeyboards
https://jhelvy.shinyapps.io/splitkbcompare
https://docs.qmo
https://docs.qmk.fm</description></item><item><title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/markdown/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 10:52:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/markdown/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mermaid Graphs</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/mermaid/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 10:52:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/mermaid/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple mermaid flowchart.
graph LR Start -- Stop For more documentations on Mermaid, view mermaid.</description></item><item><title>Some experience and thoughts about Sofle V1</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/thoughts_soflev1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/thoughts_soflev1/</guid><description>Two months ago I built a Sofle V1(Zealios 67g, DSA caps) that is my daily driver, but I have to admit that I am not as happy as I think I could or should be&amp;hellip;
The reasons are the following:
This is my first column staggered keyboard, I had a few split afore because I am starting to suffer from RSI. When I switched from the Quefrency keyboard to the Sofle keyboard, I got quite a bit of pain extending from my thumb to my neck, which surprised me quite a bit because I thought it would be more ergonomic.</description></item><item><title>What is Hugo</title><link>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ursaw.github.io/posts/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hugo is a fast and modern static site generator written in Go, and designed to make website creation fun again.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>